Hello.
In this next lecture, we're going to go over how to add a checkpoint system.
To get started, if we go over to our items folder, just right click and create a new folder and call
this item images.
Head inside this folder and then briefly close on your engine and attached in this course lecture,
I'm going to make sure to include these two images.
Select them and drag both of them into Unreal Engine.
Then with both of them selected right click anchors, write actions and apply paper to detach the settings.
Then select the first right go sprite actions and extract sprites under here.
Change this to be grid and under the cell width.
Change this to be 16.
Then select any of those rights and just right click and make it a flipbook.
Next, we want to go to our campfire, right click Sprite actions and extract Sprite.
Change this to be grid and then change the cell width to be 16.
Then we'll go to extract.
If we then select all these sprites and create a flipbook.
So the idea here is our campfire is just going to look like this.
However, when our player character overlaps our campfire, we'll make it.
That's fire.
That way they know that they've updated their checkpoint.
The next thing we need to do is create our checkpoint blueprint.
So if we go back to our items, order right click and Go Blueprint class.
Select an actor and call this checkpoint.
Then if we open it up.
Under components.
I go ad and look for a paper flipbook.
And select the check point that we just made.
The unlit version.
It's kind of small.
So under scale.
Make it five.
This will just make it a bit bigger.
Then we want to go to add and look for a box collision.
And make this box collection fit around the paper flipbook.
So we can do that by playing around with the box extent values here.
So I make the Z a bit less and I also adjust it in the x axis.
You can also adjust the camera speed because it's very fast inside of here to something like one.
That way is a bit easier to move around in here.
After you've adjusted your box, go ahead and look for a scene and just call this respawn location.
Actually call the checkpoint location.
And just place this slightly above your checkpoint, then go to the box.
Scroll down and go to on component begin overlap.
And when this overlaps our player character, we're going to update that checkpoint location to be the
location of this.
So if we drag off other actor and pass to our player blueprint or whatever you call yours, then we
want to drag up here a look for set checkpoint.
And we're going to set the checkpoint to be wherever this is.
So if we drag this in and just drag up here and get what location?
And then connect this node here.
And then finally, we want to update our paper book to be the campfire lit.
So if I just drag in my paper flipbook drag up here and set flipbook and select the campfire one.
And then connect this into here.
So now if I go compile and save or close this and then drag my checkpoint to layer 20 on my y axis.
Let's move it here.
And actually, that's kind of a bad place.
But.
Well.
So if I leave it here and I go past it.
I'm not going to let this enemy kill me.
And then I should respawn at that checkpoint.
So I die, and then I respawn at that checkpoint.
Nice.
So with this, we have set up a checkpoint system.